rsjoomla.com 2018-09-02

# Privacy Policy

_Last updated: 2018-05-24_

RSJoomla! is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the RSJoomla.com Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the RSJoomla! website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

### Collection of your Personal Information

RSJoomla! collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. RSJoomla! also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by RSJoomla!. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by RSJoomla! for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the RSJoomla! Web site.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through RSJoomla! public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: RSJoomla! does not read any of your private online communications.

RSJoomla! encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from RSJoomla! so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. RSJoomla! is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the RSJoomla! and RSJoomla! family of Web sites.

### Use of your Personal Information

RSJoomla! collects and uses your personal information to operate the RSJoomla! Web site and deliver the services you have requested. RSJoomla! also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from RSJoomla!

RSJoomla! does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties.

RSJoomla! does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

RSJoomla! keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within the RSJoomla.com web site, in order to determine what RSJoomla! services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within RSJoomla! to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

We use your information to help improve the safety and reliability of our services. This includes detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, abuse, security risks, and technical issues that could harm RSJoomla!, our users, or the public. RSJoomla! Web sites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on RSJoomla! or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of RSJoomla!; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of RSJoomla!, or the public. 

### Legal grounds for processing Personal Information

We rely on one or more of the following processing conditions:

  * our legitimate interests in the effective delivery of information and services to you;
  * explicit consent that you have given;
  * legal obligations.

### How long do we hold your Personal Information?

The RSJoomla! Web site will only hold your information for as long as is necessary to provide the services you have requested or until you exercise your right to be forgotten, as explained below.

### Cookies and how we use them

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer or mobile device. They are widely used in order to make websites and software applications work, or work in a better, more efficient way. They can do this because websites and software applications can read and write these files, enabling them to recognize you and remember important information that will make your use of a website or software application more convenient (e.g., by remembering your user preferences).

Non-persistent Cookies (Sessions): These are the cookies that are essential for the RSJoomla! Web site to perform basic functions. These include those required to allow registered users to authenticate and perform account related functions. They are not stored on your computer and are cleared when the browser window is closed.

Analytic Cookies: These cookies collect information about your use of the RSJoomla! Web site and enable us to improve the way it works. For example, Analytic Cookies show us which are the most frequently visited pages on the website, allow us to see the overall patterns of usage on the RSJoomla! Web site, help us record any difficulties you have with the RSJoomla! Web site and show us whether our pages are performing or not. Analytic Cookies the RSJoomla! Web site is using are:

  * Google Analytics: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

### How do I refuse Cookies?

You may refuse to accept cookies from the RSJoomla! Web site at any time by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse cookies. Further information about the procedure to follow in order to disable cookies can be found on your Internet browser provider’s website via your help screen. You may wish to refer to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html> for information on commonly used browsers. Please be aware that if cookies are disabled, not all features of the RSJoomla! Web site may operate as intended.

### Right to be forgotten

You have the right to delete all of the data you have submitted on the RSJoomla! Web site - which includes:

  * Your RSJoomla! Web site account's username, email address, encrypted password and full name;
  * Your billing address, city, state, ZIP and country;
  * The IP address(es) you have used to purchase products from RSJoomla!;
  * The IP address(es) you have used to download files from RSJoomla!;
  * The IP address(es) you have used to vote on the RSJoomla! Web site;
  * The IP address(es) you have used to provide feedback on the RSJoomla! Web site;
  * The IP address(es) you have used to submit tickets, reply to tickets and all of the personal information you have shared in those messages, including uploaded files, Web site links, email addresses, billing information and other data you may have supplied on the RSJoomla! Web site's support & ticketing system;
  * The domains that you have registered under the My Memberships area;
  * The name, email address, IP address(es) you have used to subscribe to the RSJoomla! Web site's newsletter system;
  * The name, email address, subject, website and comment contents from the RSJoomla! Web site's commenting system;
  * The name, email address, IP address(es) you have used to post topics and topic replies on the RSJoomla! Web site's forum;

By logging into the account you wish to have removed, clicking on Customer Area - Edit My Profile - Remove my data and close my account - Yes, send me a link. A message containing an encrypted URL will be sent to your account's email address to verify ownership and to confirm that you want your account to be removed. By clicking on that encrypted URL all of the above data will be removed and you will be logged out.

You can also request such an operation to be performed manually by one of RSJoomla! employees by submitting a ticket.

### Changes to this Statement

RSJoomla! will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. RSJoomla! encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how RSJoomla! is protecting your information.

### Contact Information

RSJoomla! welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that RSJoomla! has not adhered to this Statement, please contact RSJoomla! at techsupport@rsjoomla.com. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
